Jeanne L. Noble Papers, 1955-2002
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES III. PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES
  - National Council of Negro Women (NCNW)
    - Dorothy I. Height Leadership Institute (DIHLI)
      - College Student Academy
        - Advisory Council Consultation, 13-14 Dec 1996
          - General (Box 17, Folder 16)
          - Packet (Box 17, Folder 17)
          - Report (Box 18, Folder 1)
        - Leadership Workshop, 3-6 Apr 1997
          - General (Box 18, Folder 2)
          - Agenda and attachments (Box 18, Folder 3)
          - Notebook (Box 18, Folder 4-5)
          - Speakers (Box 18, Folder 6)
          - Worship service (Box 18, Folder 7)
        - "Leadership Academy Report," Jun 1997 (Box 18, Folder 8)
        - Coaches Kickoff Training, 31 Oct-1 Nov 1998 (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Convention Training, 1995, 1997, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 10-12)
      - Egyptian Private Voluntary Organizations, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - Evaluation, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 14)
      - Financial
        - General, 1996-99, undated (Box 18, Folder 15-18)
        - Fundraising
          - General, 1998-99, undated (Box 18, Folder 19)
          - NCNW Development Office, 1998-99 (Box 18, Folder 20)
          - Drafts for grant proposals, 1998-99, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
          - B.P. Amoco Foundation, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 2)
          - Eli Lilly Foundation, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 3)
          - Rockefeller Financial Services, 1997-99 (Box 19, Folder 4)
          - Sara Lee Corporation, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 5)
          - Texaco Foundation, 1998-99 (Box 19, Folder 6)
          - W.K. Kellogg Foundation, National Leadership Program
            - General, 1996-99, undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
            - Proposal, 1993, Aug-Sep 1995 (Box 19, Folder 8-10)
            - First year report, 8 Jul 1997 (Box 19, Folder 11)
            - Year 2 report, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 12)
            - Final report, 30 Dec 1999 (Box 19, Folder 13)
            - International Leadership Summit, 6-10 Nov 1999 (Box 19, Folder 14)
            - A Practical Guide to Leadership Development, undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
            - Visitation, Apr 1996 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Newsletters, 1999, undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Sections Training
        - General, 1998-99 (Box 20, Folder 3)
        - Correspondence, 1998-99, undated (Box 20, Folder 4-6)
        - Dorothy Height letter to Sections, Mar 1999 (Box 20, Folder 7)
        - Responses from Sections (Box 20, Folder 8-9)
        - Fundraising
          - Correspondence, 1998-00 (Box 20, Folder 10)
          - Grant proposals, 1999
            - General (Box 20, Folder 11)
            - Babcock Foundation (Box 20, Folder 12)
            - Coyne Foundation (Box 20, Folder 13)
            - East Bay Community Foundation (Box 20, Folder 14)
            - Joseph Drown Foundation (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - Handouts and presentation materials, undated
        - Introduction (Box 20, Folder 16)
        - Berlo Communication System (Box 20, Folder 17)
        - Core competencies (Box 20, Folder 18)
        - D.I. Height Institute (Box 20, Folder 19)
        - Leadership (Box 20, Folder 20)
        - Leadership issues (Box 20, Folder 21)
        - Major domains of leadership (Box 20, Folder 22)
        - Planning notes (Box 20, Folder 23)
        - Presentation ideas
          - General (Box 20, Folder 24)
          - Front of room presentations (Box 21, Folder 1)
        - Training materials (Box 21, Folder 2)
        - Training model (Box 21, Folder 3)
        - 2 + 4 Community Service Delivery Model (Box 21, Folder 4)
        - What not to say (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Financial
      - General, 1996-2000 (Box 21, Folder 6-7)
      - Grant proposal to Ford Foundation, Nov 1997 (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - "Uncommon Height" benefit gala, 1998 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Handbooks
      - Logistics and Operations, undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - National Affiliates and Community-Based Sections, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Height memoir, 1998 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - HIV/AIDS Initiative
      - General, 1998 (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - Operation Prevention Project: proposal, 1998 (Box 21, Folder 14)
      - HIV/STD Prevention Training and Technical Assistance Project
        - General, 1998 (Box 21, Folder 15)
        - Reports, 1995-98 (Box 21, Folder 16-18)
    - Membership reports, 1998-99 (Box 21, Folder 19-20)
    - 48th National Convention, 1997 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - 49th National Convention, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Publications, 1995-98, undated (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Roster, Jan 1999 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Staff directories, 1998-99, undated (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Staff retreat, Dec 1998 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Stationary and blank forms, undated (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - New York University
    - General, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - "An Evaluation of the Office for African-American and Latino Student Services," 1994 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Center for Human Relations Studies: Domestic Peace Corps TrainingProgram, instructional staff, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Job Corps Center, 1965, undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous teaching materials, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - President's Commission on an All-Volunteer Armed Force, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Salzburg Seminar, 1996-98 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Task Force Team for Proposed Women Job Corps, 1964-65, undated (Box 22, Folder 8-10)
  - United States Department of Agriculture, Public Advisory Committee, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Women in Community Service, Inc., 1967-68 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Unknown institution, Theory II: Organizational Culture, spr 1991 (Box 22, Folder 13)
- SERIES IV. SPEECHES
  - Correspondence, programs, 1963-98, undated (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Publicity, 1985, undated (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Texts, programs, presentation materials
    - Speech to school counselors: incomplete typescript, late 1950s (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Speech to Delta Sigma Theta: incomplete typescript, 7 May 1959 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Presidential Report, Delta Sigma Theta Sorority, Inc., 15 Aug 1960 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - "Duty Whispers Low: Thou Must," Howard University, 16 Oct 1960 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - "The Implications of a Changing Technology," circa 1962 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - "Personal Problems in the Employment Context," Personnel Club of NewYork, 13 Feb 1962 (Box 22, Folder 20a)
    - Delta Sigma Theta 50th Anniversary, unidentified location: incomplete typescript, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - "The Drop-Out Problem," Delta Sigma Theta Sorority, Seattle, WA, 28 Feb 1964 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - "Rearing Children of Good Will-Psychological and Sociological Facts on Child Development," 8 Mar 1965 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - "Discovered: A Fifth of a Nation," Y-Teen National Conference, 9 Aug 1965 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - "Sex Morality," YWCA of Trenton, NJ, 1 Nov 1965 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - "Girl Scouting: A Cooperative Community Endeavor," GSUSA Relationships Dinner, 23 Oct 1966 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - "The Task Before Us now, If we would not perish, Is to build the earth" Girl Scout Convention, Detroit, 25 Oct 1966 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - "And Miles To Go, Before You Sleep," Commencement Address, Cazenovia College, 4 Jun 1967 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - "Riders on the Earth Together," River Bend Girl Scout Annual Dinner, Davenport, IA, 17 Mar 1970 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - "Eliminating the Credibility Gap Between Counselors and Counselees Across Racial Lines," NAWDC Convention, 23 Apr 1973 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - "Women of Vision: Daring to Venture," Delta Sigma Theta Los Angeles Alumnae Chapter Founders Day, 22 Jan 1976 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - General Session, Bishop College, undated (circa 1979) (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - "Bitch's Brew," Princeton University, 26 Feb 1981 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - "Feminism From a Black Perspective," Harvard University, 8 Mar 1983 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - "Formal Education in 1983" (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - "What is the Artistic Mission?" New Orleans, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - "Albany speech" to a Delta Sigma Theta group, Jan 1984: fragments of drafts (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - "Feminism and Black Liberation From a Black Female Perspective," Georgia State University, 20 Jan 1984 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - "Women's Issues for the Eighties and Beyond," Bucknell University, 14 Mar 1984 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Eulogy for Lillian Benbow, Detroit, 10 May 1984 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - "Retaining Our Members," Delta Sigma Theta North Manhattan Chapter Founders Day Luncheon, 26 Jan 1985 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - "Remembrances and Revelations of Things Past and the Future Yet To Come," University of North Carolina, Nov 1985 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Eulogy for Patricia Roberts Harris, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - "Contemporary Life of Blacks," National Black Coalition of Federal Aviation Employees, 23 Oct 1986 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - "Coping With Stress: Effective Strategies for Principals," Pathways to Success Weekend Conference, The Principals' Center at Brooklyn College, 15 May 1987 (Box 23, Folder 22-24)
    - "Searching for Spirituality in Feminism," College of St. Benedict Warner Lecture Series, 18 Nov 1987 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - "Facing the Twenty-First Century: Projections and Perspectives," 75th Anniversary Celebration, Delta Sigma Theta, 30 Jan 1988 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - "Making the Past Walk through the Future," Apr 1989 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - "College Education as Personal Development," 25 Apr 1990 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - "Advancement through Togetherness," NAACP Banquet, Kalamazoo, 2 Jun 1990 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - "The Challenge and Celebration of Diversity," Berkshire Community College, 4 or 5 May 1991 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - "The True Meaning of Sisterhood," Delta Sigma Theta Southwest Regional Conference Sisterhood Breakfast, New Orleans, Aug 1991 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - "Redefining Brotherhood in the Remaining Years of the Twentieth Century," National Council of Negro Women, Co-Op City Section, Bronx, NY, 27 Feb 1994 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Delta Sigma Theta Founders Day Speech, unidentified location: fragments, 1995 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - "Education for a Journey into the Unknown," Bennett College Baccalaureate Address, 18 May 1996 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - "Shaped to Its Purpose," Delta Sigma Theta Chicago Alumnae Chapter Founders Day Luncheon, 25 Jan 1997 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Notes on the Occasion of the Opening of the Hauser Center for Nonprofit Institutions, John F. Kennedy School of Government, Harvard University, 15 Apr 1997 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - "What Does It Mean-A Sorority?" Delta Sigma Theta Southern Regional Conference Sisterhood Luncheon, 15 Aug 1997 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - 50th Anniversary Celebration, Grambling State University Alumnae Chapter, Delta Sigma Theta, 8 Nov 1997 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - "What Are Sororities Supposed to Be About?" Delta Sigma Theta Birmingham Alumnae Chapter, Founder's Day, 7 Feb 1998 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - "Patricia Roberts Harris-The Personal Dimension," Tenth Anniversary of the Patricia Roberts Harris Public Affairs Program, Howard University, 13 Mar 1998 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Keynote speech, Founders Day luncheon, Savannah Alumnae Chapter, Delta Sigma Theta Sorority, Inc., 28 Mar 1998 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Keynote address, Founders Day luncheon, Connecticut State Council of Chapters, Delta Sigma Theta Sorority, Inc., 6 Feb 1999 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Founders Day Message, Huntsville Alumnae Chapter, Delta Sigma Theta Founders Day Brunch, 13 Feb 1999 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - "Are We Deltas Y2K Compliant," Delta Sigma Theta Rochester Alumnae Chapter Founders Day, 27 Mar 1999 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Delta Sigma Theta Eastern Regional Conference, 3 Jul 1999 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - "Revering Tradition: New Horizons," National Association of Negro Business and Professional Women National Convention, 20 Jul 1999 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - "'We Got Next!' Women's Sports Will Change Leadership," Oct 1999 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - "Further Notes on Spirituality," Dorothy I Height Leadership Institute, 30 Nov 1999 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Introduction for Margaret Bush Wilson, 1999? (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Speech to social workers: incomplete typescript, circa 2001 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Undated
      - "Appraising Values for a Creative Life in Freedom and Dignity," Delta Sigma Theta (Box 25, Folder 12)
      - "Barbara Jordan" (Box 25, Folder 13)
      - Civil Rights Luncheon, Delta Sigma Theta (Box 25, Folder 14)
      - "Communication: The Challenge of Changing Patterns of Living" (Box 25, Folder 15)
      - "Developing Moral and Spiritual Values through the Student Council" (Box 25, Folder 16)
      - "A Hand to Hold and a Hand to Reach," Girl Scouts (Box 25, Folder 17)
      - Maryland [Education in the Great Society] (Box 25, Folder 18)
      - "The Functions the Intercollegiate Association of Women Students Can Serve," Intercollegiate Association of Women Students (IAWS) (Box 25, Folder 19)
      - "Happy Is the Person Who Has a God Within" (Box 25, Folder 20)
      - "How Do We Establish Communication?" (Box 25, Folder 21)
      - "Integration: Who Cares and Why Bother?" (Box 25, Folder 22)
      - "Leadership Momentum: A Wheel in Motion," by Jeanne Noble and Karen Stanley (Box 25, Folder 23)
      - "The Role of Christian Women in a Changing World" (Box 25, Folder 24)
      - "Serendipity and the Deltas" (Box 25, Folder 25)
      - "Sorority Legacies and the Issues Facing Black Americans," Delta Sigma Theta (Box 25, Folder 26)
      - "Those To Whom Much Is Given: Much Is Required" (Box 25, Folder 27)
      - "Thoughts on College Administration" (Box 25, Folder 28)
      - "Triage Leadership in Critical Situations" (Box 25, Folder 29)
      - "The University and Its Students," Ball State University (Box 25, Folder 30)
      - "What Are Sororities Supposed to Be About?" (Box 25, Folder 31)
      - "What Can the Teacher Training Institutions Do to Aid Desegregation?" (Box 25, Folder 32)
      - "What Is Competent Teaching?" (Box 25, Folder 33)
      - "Where There Is No Vision the People Perish," Delta Sigma Theta Conference (Box 25, Folder 34)
      - Why I Am an Educator Involved in Public Affairs (Box 25, Folder 35)
      - "Womanpower: Present and Potential" (Box 25, Folder 36)
      - "You and Your Alma Mater" (Box 25, Folder 37)
      - YWCA, Jersey City (Box 25, Folder 38)
  - Speech fragments [by subject]
    - Affirmative action (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
    - Black Experience through Art, Drama, Dance (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Carol Gilligan (Feminism) (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - The environment (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Martin Luther King, Jr. (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - "Noble Religious Speech" (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Plight of blacks (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Political correctness (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Reciprocity (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Spirituality (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Togetherness vs. soloing (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Walter Lee Younger (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Women's organizations (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 26, Folder 15-17)
  - Speech ideas, undated (Box 26, Folder 18-23)
  - Speeches for others [editing and advice]
    - Lena Horne
      - Untitled, Feb 1966 or 1967 in Oregon (Box 26, Folder 24)
      - On the occasion of the awarding of the Spingarn Medal by the NAACP, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Rockell Metcalf, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Robert Polk, New York Council of Churches, 1980-84 (Box 26, Folder 27)
- SERIES V. WRITINGS
  - Beautiful, Also, Are the Souls of My Black Sisters: A History of the Black Woman in America, 1978
    - Book, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - General, 1980, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1966-76 (Box 27, Folder 3-4)
    - Contract and copyright registration, 1967-86 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Design, undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Guest book from autographing party, Marymount Manhattan College, Dec 1978 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Manuscript, notes and drafts
      - Chapter 6, "We Wear the Masks" (Box 27, Folder 8)
      - Chapter 7, "Speak the Truth to the People" (Box 27, Folder 9)
      - Chapter 8, "When Malindy Sings" (Box 27, Folder 10)
      - Chapter 10, "Bitch's Brew" (Box 27, Folder 11-12)
    - Permissions, 1976-78 (Box 28, Folder 1-2)
    - Reviews, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Sales, 1978-91, undated (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - "An Exploratory Study of Domestics' Views of Their Working World" (An Inquiry into the methodology of a research design formulated to gather information for a more extensive investigation.), New York University, School of Education, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - "Foreword" for book, Shared Leadership-New Concepts by Hilda O. Fortune, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - "The Higher Education of Black Women in the Twentieth Century," in Women and Higher Education: A Feminist Perspective, 1993 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - The Negro Woman's College Education: correspondence re. reprint by Garland Publishing, Inc., 1985-87 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - "Negro Women Today and Their Education," Journal of Negro Education, winter 1957 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - "Paradigm Shifts Facing Leaders of Black Women's Organizations": typescript, circa 1993 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - "A Sense of Place: Sororities, our oldest women's organizations, keep our racial memory alive," Essence, May 1985 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - "What Makes Black Women Volunteer?": typescript, Dec 1972 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous, 1991, 1999, undated (Box 28, Folder 13)
- SERIES VI. SUBJECT FILES
  - Affirmative action (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - African-Americans (Box 29, Folder 2-3)
  - African-American women (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - The arts (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Children and youth (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Communication (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Creativity and expression (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Custom House on Bowling Green (New York City) (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Education (Box 29, Folder 10-13)
  - Excellence (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Feminism (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Groups (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Human behavior (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Individuals
    - Miscellaneous (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Ailey, Alvin (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Cosby, Camille (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Crum, Albert (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Dee, Ruby (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - de Lavellade, Carmen (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Dodson, Dan W. (Box 30, Folder 11-12)
    - Harris, Patricia Roberts (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Horne, Lena (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Malveaux, Julianne (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Navratilova, Martina (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Price, Leontyne (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Stevenson, Adlai (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Winfrey, Oprah (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Leadership (Box 31, Folder 1-2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Multicultural education (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Nonprofit organizations (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Organizations (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Playbills
    - Dance (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Theater (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Political correctness (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Politics (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Race (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Religious services (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Segregation/integration (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Spirituality (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Sports
    - General (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Lattrell Sprewell (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Tennis (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Tiger Woods phenomenon (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Virtuous capital (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Volunteerism (Box 31, Folder 20)
- SERIES VII. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS AND COMPUTER MEDIA
  - Audiotapes-cassettes
    - "Message to Norma Clark," undated (Box 32)
    - "Soror Shirley Fridia," 11/21/96 and 12/5/96 (Box 32)
    - "Final Session," 5 Oct 1969 (Box 32)
    - "Core Group # 4, Reel # 1," undated (Box 32)
    - "Pre-History (Africa Oliduvai etc.)," 17 Feb 1970 (Box 32)
  - Audiotapes-open reel
    - "Ruby Dee," undated (Box 32)
    - "Service," undated (Box 32)
    - "Lena Horne Tour (National Congress of Neighborhood Women), Jeanne Noble, Moderator," 1966 (Box 32)
    - "Delta Sigma Theta Conv #1," undated (Box 32)
    - "Delta Sigma Theta Album, Side 2," undated (Box 32)
    - "Delta Sigma Theta, Hillcrest Country Club," reels 2-5, 8 Dec 1974 (Box 32)
  - Video-DVD: "The House That Deltas Built: A Virtual Reality Tour," 1998 (Box 33)
  - Video-VCR tapes
    - "Delta Sigma Theta Signature Gala," part 1 and part 2, 13 Jul 1992 (Box 33)
    - "NCNW Headquarters Grand Opening," and "The Vision of Mary McLeod Bethune," undated (Box 33)
    - "In the Spirit of Sisterhood," Delta Sigma Theta, 1991 (Box 33)
    - "NCNW Inaugural Weekend Highlights," undated (Box 33)
    - "Installation of Chancellor Dr. Green," 3 Mar 1988 (Box 33)
  - Computer disks, 3 ½ inch (6), 1996-97, undated (Box 33)
- SERIES VIII. ARTIFACTS
  - Delta Sigma Theta: Arts and Letters Award, Westchester Alumnae Chapter 35th Anniversary, 1994 (Box 34)
  - North Shore Club, National Association of Negro Business and Professional Women's Clubs, National Sojourner Truth Meritorious Service Award, 1980 (Box 34)
  - Keys to cities
    - El Paso del Norte (Box 34)
    - Los Angeles, California (Box 34)
  - Girl Scouts USA statuette (Box 34)
  - National Council of Negro Women: tote bag (Box 34)
  - Paperweight: Alvin Ailey organization "to Jeanne Noble for her untiring efforts over the years" (Box 34)
  - Plaques
    - Black Cultural Center, University of Akron, 1983 (Box 34)
    - From students in the guidance and counseling program, 1987 (Box 34)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - Certificate of appreciation mounted on wood, to Jeanne L. Noble from the Defense Advisory Committee on Women in the Services, U.S. Department of Defense, 1 Jan 1960 (Box 35)
  - Plaque honoring Jeanne L. Noble for outstanding achievement in advancing social progress, on the occasion of the YWCA of the USA and National Council of Jewish Women's joint celebration of a half century of social action, 1961 (Box 35)
  - Certificate of recognition from National Conference of Christians and Jews, 18 Feb 1963 (Box 36)
  - Letter of thanks for service to National Advisory Commission on Selective Service from President Lyndon Baines Johnson, 24 Mar 1967 (Box 36)
  - Certificate of appreciation from the members of the President's Task Force on the War Against Poverty, undated (Box 36)
  - Certificate of appreciation in recognition of service on Commission on an All-Volunteer Armed Force from President Richard Nixon, undated (Box 36)
  - Certificate of appointment to the National Advisory Council on Education, President Gerald R. Ford, 9 Jun 1975 (Box 36)
  - Delta Sigma Theta Commission on Ritual and Ceremonies, Membership Intake Training Program notes, 1983 (Box 36)
  - Commendation from city of Miami, Florida, 11 Jan 1985 (Box 36)
  - Commendation from Metropolitan Dade County Florida, 12 Jan 1985 (Box 36)
  - Poster "In Celebration of Black Women: A Salute to the 15th Anniversary of Essence Magazine," by the Gillette Company, Personal Care Division, May 1985 (Box 36)
  - Savannah Herald issues for 11 Mar and 25 Mar 1998 with articles re Jeanne Noble speech to Delta Sigma Theta Torchbearer Luncheon (Box 36)
  - "Dr. Noble Speaks" photograph of a classroom with calligraphy, undated (Box 36)
  - Mounted unidentified photograph of an African-American man. (Box 36)